wimbledon.com 2014-03-27

# The Championships, Wimbledon 2013 - Official Site by IBM - Your Privacy

**Introduction**  
This statement discloses the privacy policy of the official website of The All England Lawn Tennis Club (Championships) Limited (‘AELTC’) and of The Championships, Wimbledon.

The AELTC, also referred to in this Privacy Policy as ‘we’, ‘us’, or ‘our’,  is the organisation responsible for day-to-day planning and staging of The Championships, Wimbledon. IBM, as the Official Supplier of Information Technology, provides the equipment and services to build and host the Wimbledon website. We are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy.

We explain below the way in which we collect and use your information and personal data. By using the Site, you consent to the use (including transfer) of such information as described below.

 **What information do we collect, and how do we collect it?**  
The AELTC intends to give you as much control as possible over your personal information. When you visit the Site, our web servers automatically collect certain data that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website, such as your IP (Internet Protocol) address and information relating to which pages have been viewed. This information is discarded once analysed. 

We collect information voluntarily submitted by you, such as your email address and other contact details for correspondence. If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence. 

 **Cookies** ** **  
The Site uses cookies. A cookie is a small file containing an identity code. Your computer accepts the cookie and stores it. When you next visit the Site, the code is retrieved, allowing an individual visitor or computer to be recognised.

Cookies are used for a variety of purposes, including providing personalised web pages and recognising your choice of language. Cookies do not cause harm to your computer, but, if you wish to stop your computer accepting cookies, go to the help section of your internet browser (for example, Internet Explorer or Firefox) where you will find information on how to do this. You can opt out of using cookies at any time.

 **How the AELTC uses cookies**  
Cookies on the Wimbledon website are used in the following ways:  
i) Analytics  
The Wimbledon website uses analytics tools to collect information about how people use its sites. This helps us make sure sites are meeting users’ needs and to find out how we could improve.

Analytics cookies store very simple information about a user’s session, such as what pages people visit, how long they are on the site, how they got there and what they click on. Information supplied by cookies helps the AELTC to analyse the profile of visitors and provide them with a better experience. These cookies expire after a set time period. 

Analytics cookies do not collect or store users’ personal information (for example, names or addresses), so this information cannot be used to identify individuals. The AELTC does not allow analytics companies to use or share its analytics data.

ii) Serving advertisements  
The advertisements seen on the Wimbledon website are served by a third-party ad serving provider called Sport Syndicator. The system uses cookies to allow monitoring of the effectiveness of the ads (for example, by using statistical analysis cookies) and make the ads more relevant to users.  

iii) Third party cookies  
Some cookies are not set by the AELTC but by other sites which provide a service or functionality, such as embedded ‘share’ buttons to enable users of the site to easily share articles with their friends through popular social networks. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged in to their service. These are known as third-party cookies. Managing, deleting or blocking these cookies requires you to visit the websites of these third parties. 

 **How to manage cookies**  
Internet browsers allow users to manage their cookies. They can set their devices to accept all cookies, to let them know when a cookie has been set, or never to receive cookies.

Each browser works in a different way: use the ‘Help’ menu in your browser to find out to change your cookie preferences. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone you should refer to your handset manual.

Please be aware that disabling cookies completely means that certain personalised features will not then be provided to that user and therefore they may not be able to make full use of all of the website’s features.

You can learn more about cookies and how to manage them at [AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "Information about cookies") 

 **How do we use your private information?** ** **  
The ways in which we use your information will vary depending on the kind of information you provide and the purpose for which you have provided it. This section sets out the different ways we may use your information.

We may use anonymous information, like your IP address, to compile statistics, to assess the usage of the Site and to customise the Site's content, layout and services.  This will allow us to improve the Site and the services provided through it.

 We may integrate your personal data from our various databases to form a single view to allow us to have an effective and efficient communication with you.

 We may provide your private information to any third party that administers any facility, service or promotion operated via the Site on our behalf.  

We may contact you to ask if you would like to complete a survey or answer some market research questions including in relation to (i) the services and/or products available on the Site and (ii) the way in which you use the Site.

Where you have specifically consented for us to do so, we will pass your information onto carefully selected third parties, such as the Lawn Tennis Association, so that they can provide you with relevant information about products and/or services in which we think you might be interested.

We do not sell, re-use, rent, lease, loan, trade or otherwise divulge the addresses on our lists to anyone unless you specifically consent to provide such information to a third party partner. 

If you would prefer not to receive additional information from us on any matter relating to this website and The Championships, please indicate this by ticking the relevant box when you fill in your email address. 

 **Shop**  
The Wimbledon Online Shop is operated by a company called KitBag on our behalf. 

As well as the general uses listed above, by using the Shop website or by signing up to merchandise e-newsletters, you agree that we may use your information for the following purposes:

For the purposes of fulfilling orders you make on the shop website and sending you email communications in connection with those orders.

To respond to any queries you make about the items on the Shop website.

To send you information about other merchandise in which you might be interested.

Purchases from the Shop are governed by [the Wimbledon Online Shop terms and conditions](http://shop.wimbledon.com/stores/wimbledon/help/help.aspx?hpg=terms).   
 **  
Data protection compliance** ** **  
We shall collect, store and use (‘process’) your personal data in a manner that is compatible with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the ‘Act’).

We shall endeavour to keep your personal data accurate and up-to-date. If you apply to register with us, you consent by doing so to our processing the personal data that you submit for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you, which can be exercised in accordance with the Act.  You can (if you pay a small fee to cover administrative expenses) request a copy of information about you held by us at any time by sending us a written and signed request. 

 **When we are required to disclose information** ** **  
We shall disclose your private information if we reasonably believe that we are required to do so by law, regulation, court order or any competent governmental, statutory or public authority or to protect our rights and property. 

We may also cooperate with a law enforcement agency in any official investigation, and we may disclose your private information to that agency in doing so.

 **Internet awareness** ** **  
Whenever you voluntarily post information about you in public areas of the Site, you should be aware that such information can be accessed by the public and may in turn be used by others to send you unsolicited communications. Please exercise discretion in deciding what information you provide.

 **Other websites** ** **  
The Site may contain links to other websites which are outside our control and are not covered by the terms of this Privacy Policy.

If you access other websites using the links provided, the operators of those websites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

 **Security of your private information** ** **  
Once we have received your private information, we shall endeavour to protect it by using physical, managerial and technical procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access to it.

We cannot, however, guarantee the security of any private information provided to us in an email or in online form while it is being transmitted to us, as the internet is a potentially non-secure method of information transfer. Any such transmission is at your own risk.

Subject to our obligations under the Act, we do not accept any responsibility for any loss, disruption or damage to your data or your computer system which may occur while using interactive features of the Site.

As best practice, we also strongly recommend that you regularly run an anti-virus programme on all material downloaded from the internet.

 **Updating your information and opting out** ** **  
If you would like to cancel your registration for e-newsletters you can do so at any time by following the relevant link in any e-newsletter. If you cancel your registration for e-newsletters you will no longer receive any e-newsletters and you will not be able to re-subscribe using the same email address.

 **Tickets  
** As well as the general uses listed above, by applying for tickets, you agree that we may use your information for the following purposes:

To provide you with tickets, services, account information and support. For example, we might send you emails about your ticket purchase.

To identify trends and interests. We use your information to get to know what your preferences might be so we can improve our offering to you and so that your experience with us is more relevant and personal. We may combine information we get from you with information about you we get from third parties, including to analyse customer behaviour.

To monitor and improve our products, services, and websites. We analyse information prevent or detect unlawful behaviour or to protect or enforce legal rights. For example, we may use your information to prevent ticket touting, misuse of our intellectual property, or fraud (including credit card fraud) or other crimes.

For security purposes. We may use your information to protect the security of our company, employees, our customers, third parties and/or our/their property as permitted by law.

For market research purposes. We may contact you as part of market research we are carrying out.

For marketing purposes. Where you've agreed, you may be contacted by us by email, text message, telephone or other means with information or offers regarding our upcoming events, products or services.

 **Updates to this Privacy Policy** ** **  
If we update or otherwise change this Privacy Policy, we shall post the changes on this page and indicate at the top of this page when this Privacy Policy was last updated. Your continued use of the Site indicates your agreement to any such changes.

 **Language** ** **  
Please note that this Privacy Policy has been drawn up in the English language and shall be interpreted in the English language.

Where this Privacy Policy (or any part of it) is translated into any other language and there is a conflict in meaning between the English language version and such translated version, the English language version shall prevail in all respects.

 **How can you contact us?**  
We welcome your views about the website and our Privacy Policy. You can contact us (link) with any queries, complaints or comments.

 **TERMS AND CONDITIONS**  
The use of the Wimbledon website at [ **www.wimbledon.com**](http://www.wimbledon.com/)  (the "Site") is subject to the following terms and conditions which you should read. The Site is managed by The All England Lawn Tennis Club (Championships) Limited (AELTC) (referred to as "We" or "us" or "our" below). In entering the Site, you as a user ("You" or "Your") are accepting our terms and conditions.

All material on the Site or made available via the Site (referred to in this section as the "Content") belongs to us or to third parties who have allowed us to use and display their material. You may use the Content only for your personal, non-commercial use, and provided that you acknowledge the copyright owner. You may not otherwise reproduce, modify or in any way commercially exploit any of the Content. 

Information on this Site is posted in good faith and updated regularly. However, we cannot guarantee the completeness and accuracy of the information shown. Due to the nature of electronic distribution via the Internet, we do not give any warranties or make any representations in respect of the Site. In particular, the Site is provided on an "as is", "with all faults" and "as available" basis.

So far as lawfully possible, and other than as specifically provided in relation to products purchased or otherwise obtained through the Site, we exclude all liability to you in contract or delict (negligence) (other than where negligence by us gives rise to personal injury or death) including without limitation:  
(i) any implied conditions regarding the satisfactory quality or fitness for a particular purpose of the Site;  
(ii) any express or statutory conditions relating to the Site; and  
(iii) any conditions or duties regarding accuracy or completeness of the Site.

Additionally, we make no representation that the Site is free from infection by viruses or anything else that has contaminating or destructive properties. We make every effort to check and test material at all stages of production. However, it is always wise for you to run an anti-virus program on all material downloaded from the Internet. We cannot accept any responsibility for any loss, disruption or damage to your data or your computer system which may occur whilst using material derived from this website.

Other than as specifically provided in relation to products purchased or obtained free of charge through the Site or as specified elsewhere in this section of the Site entitled "Use of this site and our liability to you", we shall not be liable to pay any money to you by way of compensation for any loss suffered by you as a result of use of the Site including by way of example any loss of profits, loss of goodwill or reputation, or loss of anticipated savings.

The Site contains links to other websites provided by both connected organisations and independent third parties (referred to in this paragraph as "Third Party Sites"), either directly or through frames (i.e. material which is taken from a third party site but which is shown as though it is part of the Site). Where possible, we will make clear where such links are being made. 

We are not responsible for the reliability or content of Third Party Sites and other than as expressly provided on this Site, shall not be a party to, or in any way be responsible for, any transaction concerning goods or services available from such Third Party Sites. 

The existence of links to other websites on this website should not be taken as endorsement of any kind of the other websites in question. We cannot guarantee that these links will work all the time and we have no control over the availability of the linked pages.
